按说我们失去了那么多
You'd think with all we've lost,
失败会让我们崩溃
that defeat would break us.
但我们之所以能在这里
But the only reason we're here
就是因为我们最初不肯死去
is we refused to die in the first place.
我们如严寒一般坚持
We're as persistent as the cold,
永远困在冰下
forever trapped beneath the ice.
我们眼睛盯着地面 忍着
We keep our eyes on the floor, dig our nails in,
做好准备
and prepare to brace...
你们以为我想来吗
Do you think I want to be here?
你们以为威尔福德先生希望我来这么做吗
That Mr. Wilford wants me to be doing this?
雪国列车是这世界仅剩的东西了
Snowpiercer is all that's left of the world.
-妈妈 -不要
- Mommy! - Please, no, no.
我们每个人都对永动机
Each of us has a personal responsibility
负有责任
to the Engine Eternal.
你们车尾人都不需要做什么
You Tailies barely have to do anything.
是吧 就坐好了 别叛乱
Yeah? Just sit around and don't rebel.
这是你们的错
This is your fault.
快点做完吧
Let's get it over with.
不要 别
Please don't. Please.
让我来吧
Do it to me instead.
那有什么道理
Where's the logic in that?
她只是个小姑娘
She's just a little girl.
对 小姑娘 但帮忙杀了六个男人
Yeah, a little girl who helped to kill six men.
我是她妈妈
I'm her mother.
是我的错
It's my fault.
是我让她帮忙反叛的
I let her help the rebellion.
好啊
Finally.
总算有人有道德底线 愿意为自己的行为
Someone with the moral fortitude to take responsibility
承担责任
for their actions.
好
Alright.
宝贝
Oh, baby.
过来 宝贝
Oh, come here, baby.
没事
It's okay. It's okay.
It's okay.
没事 亲爱的
It's okay, honey.
你真勇敢
You're so brave.
没事的
It's gonna be okay.
看着我
Look at me.
去找你哥哥
Go to your brother.
坚强点 温妮佩格
Be strong, Winnipeg.
我爱你
I love you.
无票的乘客
Unticketed passengers,
威尔福德先生判你们叛乱 谋杀
Mr. Wilford has found you guilty of insurrection, murder,
扰乱列车秩序罪成立
and disturbing the order of the train.
作为偷渡者 你们无权进行庭审
As stowaways, you have no right to trial
或进行上诉
or the established appeals process.
莱顿 信守你的承诺 听见了吗
Layton, keep your promise. You hear me?
因永动机的慷慨和仁慈
It is only by the largess and mercy of Our Engine Eternal
你们被允许存活至今
that you have been allowed to live thus far.
会没事的
It's gonna be okay.
会没事的 会没事的
It's gonna be okay. It's gonna be okay.
会没事的
It's gonna be okay.
奉威尔福德工业之命
So by the authority of Wilford Industries,
你们被判在抽屉中进入永恒假死状态
you are hereby sentenced to indefinite suspension in the drawers.
愿上帝怜悯你们
May God have mercy on your spark.
他们可以夺取我们的肢体
They can take our limbs...
我们的孩子
our children...
我们的领袖
our leaders.
他们可以试着夺取我们的尊严
They keep trying to take our dignity,
但任何幸存者都会告诉你
but any survivor will tell you
他们早就把尊严留在鬼门关了
they check their dignity at death's door.
他们偷走的越多 我们就越有人性
The more they steal from us, the more human we become.
当我们吞食掉有着1001节车厢的
Humanity will fill our bellies one day...
雪国列车上的富人时
...when we eat the rich of Snowpiercer,
总有一天人性会填满我们的肚腹
1,001 cars long.
雪国列车
第一季 第二集
悠着点
Easy, girl.
最近的4级...
Recent Class 4...
所以我重新设置了铲雪机
That's why I reconfigured the plow.
引擎
但我这里看不到情况
But I can't see conditions here.
早上好 工程师们
Good morning, engineers.
早上好
Good morning.
我们的速度总引起雪崩
Our speed keeps trigger avalanches.
一小时内已经第二次了
Second one in an hour.
每次革命后 这段路就愈发崎岖
This stretch gets rougher every revolution.
有这样的暴风雪 梅
With a storm like this, Mel,
无论我黑进多少老苏联卫星都不管用
it doesn't matter how many old Russian satellites I hack.
我们现在就是在抓瞎前进
We're basically running blind right now.
保持速度
Keep the speed up.
我今天都会在列车后方忙
I'm gonna be busy downtrain today.
会很麻烦的 三等厢那个谋杀案怎么样了
It's gonna get hairy. How's your murder in Third?
是三等厢的两起谋杀案
It's two murders in Third,
尾部车厢一场暴动
an uprising in the Tail,
一等厢还有闹剧
and drama in First
他们搞得好像有黑帮逼近了一样
where they're acting like there's a mob at their door.
伙计们 说回引擎
Guys, back to the engine, please.
不要在这地形高速前进
Do not highball this terrain.
我建议减速12%
I recommend we throttle back 12%.
哈维 我不能宣布停电
Javi, I can't announce blackouts.
今天不行
Not today.
你可以为了安全减速 或者保证供电
Well, you can slow for safety, or you can have electricity.
保持速度
Maintain speed.
她会稳住的
She'll hold the track.
你觉得她还能坚持多久
How long do you think she can keep this up?
哈维 我们已经开了七年了 而且还在继续
Well, Javi, we're going on seven years and counting.
所有乘客请注意
Attention all passengers.
威尔福德工业祝您早上好
Wilford Industries wishes you a good morning.
-外面的气温为零下100度 -起来
- The temperature outside is minus 100 degrees. - Get up.
你今天早上感觉怎么样 司闸员
How you feeling this morning, Brakeman?
坐下
Sit down.
别太习惯了
Don't get used to it.
嗯 她可能正经历创伤后应激障碍
Yeah. She might be experiencing some PTSD symptoms
因为我救了她一命
'cause I saved her life.
你是去救你的伙伴
You were in it to save your buddies.
我什么都不欠你
I don't owe you a thing.
你们今天会相处得很愉快的
You two are gonna have a great day.
-清洁 -排好队
- Sanitation! - Alright, back it up!
你们知道流程
You know the drill.
清洁细节
Sanitation detail.
你们要目视地面
You will keep your eyes down.
不许跟有票乘客互动
You will not interact with ticketed passengers.
-看着点 车尾人 -你可以好好说的
- Watch it, Tailie. - You can just ask nicely.
你们的人杀了他们的朋友
Your people killed their friends.
你似乎没意识到自己有多不受欢迎
I don't think you realize how unpopular you are.
他们杀了14个我们的人
Yeah, well, they killed 14 of mine.
莱顿 来吧
Layton, come on.
那是一只很好看的胳膊
It was a good, clean arm.
碎得好看极了
It shattered very nicely.
但这对福爵一家来说还不够
But, no, that's not enough for the Folgers.
他们支持沙玛
They're with Sharma.
她拉拢了一帮人
She's worked up a nice head of steam.
我会对付她
I'll handle her.
等一下
Oh, wait a minute.
-真糟糕 -好了
- Oopsy. - There you go.
你是头等厢委员会主席
You're the First Class Committee Chair.
你提出 否则我来
Table it or I will.
大家坐车久了 腿还好吗
How are everyone's train legs?
你们早上是不是没吃晕车药
Did we miss our Gravol this morning?
其实 梅兰妮 我们觉得晕车药
Actually, Melanie, we don't think that Gravol
不是处理车尾叛乱的最好处方[对策]
is the best prescription for a rebellion in the Tail.
"叛乱"这个词有点夸张了
I think "Rebellion" Is overstating it.
格雷指挥官在数分钟内就控制了事态
Commander Grey had it contained in minutes.
死了六个人
Six dead.
安保人员可不是从树上长出来的 梅兰妮
Security forces don't grow on trees, Melanie.
我们还担忧另一件事
And we have a second concern.
三等厢那起谋杀 你试图不声张
The murder in Third -- the one you tried to keep quiet
因为你调用了一个车尾人协助调查
because you pulled up a Tailie to assist the investigation.
是威尔福德先生选出了最适合那工作的人选
Mr. Wilford picked the best person for the job.
他以前是凶案警探
He's a former homicide detective.
车尾有个警察吗
There's a policeman in the Tail?
后面什么人都有
There's a bit of everything back there.
别担心 福爵太太
Don't worry, Mrs. Folger.
关键是 在叛乱期间
The point is, upgrading this man
给这个男人升厢 会传递错误的讯息
in the middle of a rebellion, it sends the wrong message.
如果威尔福德先生需要帮助
If Mr. Wilford needs help,
我当过25年律师
I was a lawyer for 25 years.
我很愿意分享我的见解
I'd be happy to share insights
只要你分享调查的详情
if you share details of the investigation.
作为律师
Well, as a lawyer,
你明白那信息是特许保密的
you understand that information is privileged.
我都不知道芬克尔斯坦 布兰克森
And I didn't know that Finklestein, Branxom,
和福爵杀过人 妈妈
and Folger did murders, Mom.
你们就笑吧
Go ahead and laugh.
我家人也许不认为我能干 梅兰妮
My family may not think I'm capable, Melanie,
但大冰封教会我们 每个人都有能力杀人
but the Freeze taught us all we have the capacity to kill.
所以所有人都是嫌犯
Which is why everyone is a suspect.
包括你
Even you.
续咖啡吗 莱拉
Do you want more coffee, Lilah?
慢用你的早餐
Well, enjoy your breakfast.
今天不适合乱跑 要坐稳扶好
And, um, it's a good day to stay seated and ready to brace.
-谢谢 -您还需要什么吗
- Thank you. - Can I get you anything else?
您的早餐如何
How's your breakfast?
棒极了 谢谢
Wonderful. Thank you.
车尾垃圾来了
Tailie tossed coming through.
老兄 继续走
Buddy, keep moving.
准备好侦查了吗 警探
You ready to detect, Detective?
管道工杰克斯·卡特
Tunnelman Jakes Carter.
-拜托 -他是发现尸体的人
- Come on. - He's the guy who found the body.
我连值两班 现在是我的午休时间
I'm working a double. This is my lunch break.
很好 我跟你一起午休
Great, I'll join you.
我要一份小份 不用给他
Hey, small for me. He's good.
我认识你
I know you.
你是那个车尾警探
You're that Tailie detective.
听着 我已经交代过一次事发经过了
Look, I already told what happened once.
我是列车警探
I'm the Train Detective,
威尔福德先生让我听你亲口说说
and Mr. Wilford asked me to come hear it from you directly.
你对此有意见吗
Do you have a problem with that?
没 没意见
No. No problem.
我当时在农业区下面做日常检修工作
I was doing routine maintenance under Ag-Sec.
就是普通的一天 绕着地球转 不是吗
It was just another day, 'round and 'round we go, right?
我撬开一块地板 他就在那里
I pop a floor panel, and there he is --
没有手臂 没有腿 没有老二
no arms, no legs, and no dick.
谁能进入附属列车
Who has access to the subtrain?
每天都有好几百人经过
Hundreds of people go through every day --
工人 乘客 所有舱位都会
workers, passengers, all classes.
不同舱位间的检查点是什么样的
What are the checkpoints like between classes?
-有 -别回答
- There's -- - Don't answer that.
我在试图评估你能把尸体移动多远距离
I-I am trying to assess how far you can move a body.
好吧
A'ight.
就这些吗
That's it?
还有一个问题
Nah, one more thing.
你在吃什么
What's that you're eating?
这是列车上最棒的牛肉面
This is the best beef noodles on the train right here.
要是我们还需要审问你 别那么混蛋
Hey, if we need you again, don't be an asshole.
好了 问重点
Okay, stay on point.
离尸检还有两个小时
We got two hours till the autopsy,
妮基·吉奈特还在昏迷中 限制出入
and Nikki Genet is still unconscious, restricted access.
等你吃完牛肉面
Well, when you're done with your beef,
我们去她以前工作的夜车转转
we'll take a trip to the Nightcar where she used to work.
第一起案子的现场
Scene of the first crime.
不错
It's good.
是假死配方的问题还是时长的问题
Is the issue with the suspension formula or the duration?
那是个复杂的相互作用
That's a complicated interplay.
我有好好照顾她
I-I've taken very good care of her.
她的肌肉质量
Her muscle mass
我只是想知道她能不能醒过来
I'm just trying to figure out if she's gonna come out of it.
逐渐地
Slowly.
我希望
I hope.
或许你该建议
Maybe you should recommend
威尔福德先生暂停整个项目
Mr. Wilford put the entire program on hold.
不行
No.
告诉威尔福德先生 我会弄个水落石出的
Tell Mr. Wilford. I'll get to the bottom of it.
求你了
Please.
那我们最好去看看你的数据
Then we better go look at your data.
夜 夜车
Night-Nightcar.
欢迎来到夜车
Welcome to the Nightcar.
♪说不是这样 乔 求你♪
♪ Say it ain't so, Joe, please♪
♪告诉我这不是真的♪
♪ Say it ain't so ♪
♪那不是我想听到的 乔♪
♪ That's not what I wanna hear, Joe ♪
♪我有权知道♪
♪ And I've got a right to know ♪
♪说不是这样 乔 求你♪
♪ Say it ain't so, Joe, please ♪
♪告诉我这不是真的♪
♪ Say it ain't so ♪
♪我很确定他们在说谎 乔 求你了♪
♪ I'm sure they're telling us lies, Joe, please ♪
♪告诉我们这并不是真的♪
♪ Tell us it ain't so ♪
♪他们说我们的英雄使出了他的王牌♪
♪ They told us that our hero has played his trump card ♪
♪他不知道该如何继续♪
♪ He doesn't know how to go on ♪
奥德丽小姐 这是她的舞台
Miss Audrey. It's her place.
♪我们依附着他的魅力和坚定的笑容♪
♪ We're clinging to his charm and determined smile ♪
♪但好日子已经远去♪
♪ But the good-ole days are gone ♪
♪幻想和帝国或许在破碎♪
♪ The image and the empire may be falling apart ♪
♪钱变得稀有♪
♪ The money has gotten scarce ♪
♪一个人的话凝聚着整个国家♪
♪ One man's word held the country together ♪
♪但真相却越来越凶狠♪
♪ But the truth is getting fierce ♪
♪说不是这样 乔 求你♪
♪ Say it ain't so, Joe, please ♪
♪告诉我这不是真的♪
♪ Say it ain't so ♪
♪我们对你深怀希望 乔♪
♪ We've pinned our hopes on you, Joe ♪
♪而他们在破坏我们的演出♪
♪ And they're ruinin' our show ♪
我看见妮基跟爱德华在房里 他是她的常客
I found Nikki in the room with Edward, her regular.
她完全不清楚当时发生了什么
She had no idea what was happening.
我很确定 被真正的杀手下了毒
Drugged, I'm sure, by the real killer.
但威尔福德先生需要快速解决
But Mr. Wilford needed a quick resolution
找个凶手关进抽屉
a body in a drawer.
这次不一样
This time will be different.
了解一下 梅兰妮·卡维尔当时扮演什么角色
Just for context, what was Melanie Cavill's role back then?
这问题不错
That's a good question.
但愿是她说的那样
It's her lips to God's ear, isn't it?
免费招待
On the house.
旧世界的烈酒
Old-world spirits.
为感谢你的服务准备的特调
A little something special for you service.
什么服务
What service is that?
你可以扭转威尔福德的不公
You could reverse a Wilford injustice.
这对三等厢来说是奢望
That hope is in short supply in Third.
我纳闷很久了
I've been wondering for a long time
你们到底在夜车上做什么
what exactly it is you do up here in the Nightcar.
我们提供顿悟 亲爱的
We offer epiphanies, darling.
让他去亲身体验吧
Let him go see for himself.
我不能让他离开我的视线
I can't let him outta my sight.
如果你想让这次的结果与妮基的不同
If you want this to be different than Nikki,
就得让他知道妮基当时做了什么
he needs to understand what she did.
给你20分钟
You can have 20 minutes.
我就在这里等着
I'll be waiting right here.
说吧 这个案子是有什么
Alright, what is it about this case
不能当着司闸员告诉我的
you couldn't tell me in front of a Brakeman?
要有耐心 莱顿先生
Patience, Mr. Layton.
你想了解我们在这里做什么
You wanted to know what we do here.
要给我上好货吗
You gonna give me the good stuff?
夜车其实从来不是一家妓院 安德烈
The Nightcar's never actually been a brothel, Andre.
世界瓦解时 大多数人需要的是别的东西
When the world ended, most people needed something else --
他们需要悲痛 与失去的一切产生联系
to grieve, to connect with everything we've lost.
我开发了夜车体验
I've developed the Nightcar Experience
这样我们就能作为个人或集体来治愈疗伤
so we could heal, individually and collectively.
你是心理治疗师
You a therapist?
放松 安德烈
Relax, Andre.
放空大脑
Clear your mind.
还记得我们以前在车尾是怎么冥想的吗
Remember how we used to meditate in the Tail?
嗯 你走之后我就没做过了
Yeah, I gave that up when you left.
把自己放心交给她
You're in good hands.
我们肯定会很快再见的
I'm sure we'll meet again soon.
闭上眼睛
Close your eyes.
你还记得水的感觉吗 安德烈
Do you remember the water, Andre?
我记得
I remember.
坠落
Falling.
自由流动
Free-flowing.
这种仍然清醒的元素
An element still awake.
倾听风声
Hear the wind.
地球依然活着
Earth is still alive.
飞鸟
The birds.
树叶
The leaves.
记住这些树
Remember the trees...
草
the grass...
还有太阳
the sun.
我感受到了
I can feel it.
你在哪
Where are you?
我回家了
I'm home.
我看见你了
I see you.
打扰一下 女士
Excuse me, ma'am?
怎么了
Yes?
我得看看你的证件
Yeah, I'm gonna need to see some identification.
我...
Oh, I...
没什么好紧张的
No reason to be nervous.
别被警徽吓着了
Don't let the badge intimidate you.
别担心
Oh, don't worry.
我没被吓到
It doesn't.
我想你了
I missed you.
你在哪
Where are you?
我饿了
I'm hungry.
我要饿死了
I'm starving.
来了
I got you.
甜甜圈
Ooh, doughnuts!
传统口味 韦伯店的
Old-school. Weber's.
你的最爱
Your favorite.
我爱你 安德烈
I love you, Andre.
什么
What?
扎拉·费拉米
Zarah Ferami...
你想这样吗
you wanna do this thing?
结婚 把这变成真的
Get married? You know, make it real?
我们是真实的
We are real.
我知道 没错 不过更加真实一点
I know, yes, but realer.
说出那些誓词
Say the words --
相守 相惜 疾病 健康 这些话
hold, cherish, sickness, health, all that shit.
我担心的不是我们 安德烈
I'm not worried about us, Andre.
我担心的是这个世界
I'm worried about the world.
有我在 扎拉
I got you, Zarah.
任何时候都是
In good times and bad.
我知道 安德烈
I know, Andre.
我愿意
I do.
我只想抱着你到永远
I just wanted to hold you forever.
说清楚 平时我是不会这样做的
To be clear, this is not how it usually goes.
你想告诉我什么
What'd you want to tell me?
威尔福德的人没有把肖恩的所有事告诉你
Wilford's people aren't telling you everything about Sean.
我觉得他是个告密者 因为他很幸运
I think he was a snitch, 'cause he was lucky.
他有特别待遇
Like, he got perks.
什么样的特别待遇
What kinda perks?
我们中了婴儿彩
We won the Baby Lottery.
这种运气通常意味着你有一个在前列车厢的"朋友"
That kinda luck usually means you have a "Friend" Uptrain.
我本来准备做的
I was gonna do it.
我本来要和肖恩生个孩子
I was gonna have a baby with Sean.
你爱他吗
Did you love him?
这是雪国列车 安德烈
It's Snowpiercer, Andre.
我不会让他们把这起谋杀案归咎于你的 扎拉
Look, I'm not gonna let them pin this murder on you, Zarah,
但当我在这里的时候
but while I'm up here,
我得对车尾负责
I have a responsibility to the Tail.
如果你留在这里后果会很严重吗
Would it be so terrible if you stayed up here?
和我一起
With me?
时间到了
Time's up.
我在夜车工作时可没遇到这样的事
Not what my Nightcar trip looked like.
很遗憾
Unfortunately.
你应该是去了解妮基的情况
You were supposed to be getting context on Nikki.
这叫得寸进尺
That's called taking a mile.
有时警探工作需要与人亲密接触
Sometimes detective work requires a personal touch.
先说清楚 我以前从没做过尸检
Just to be clear, I've never done an autopsy before.
但我是前海军医疗队的
But I'm Ex-Navy Medical Corps,
所以我知道怎么找创伤和
so I do know how to look for trauma and --
诊断创伤后应激障碍
oh, and diagnose PTSD.
我估计我们现在都得了 不是吗
I guess we've all got that now, don't we?
我从阿富汗退役后
I formed out of Afghanistan for a one-year gig
来威尔福德的梦幻列车上做一年的医生
as a medic on Wilford's Dreamliner as a medic.
谁知道会遇到世界大冰封
Who knew the world would freeze
这工作就没完没了了
and the job would last forever?
这里的铁青色是淤积的血液
This lividity here, that's pooled blood.
表示他死后脸朝下趴了一会儿
Means he lay face-down for a while postmortem.
然后他们才转移了他
They moved him later.
你昨天看到的还有什么没说的
What else did you see yesterday and not share?
你说说看
You tell me.
好啊
Okay.
多处捆绑痕迹
Multiple ligature marks.
嗯
Yeah.
反复窒息
Choked in and out.
他们想延长砍掉他老二的时间
They wanted to drag out chopping his dick off.
四肢看起来都被锯掉了
Stumps look sawn off.
看上去是这样锯的 向下
Looks like this way -- down.
可能是用的钢锯
Hacksaw maybe?
所以他的脸被翻过来后四肢才被锯掉
So the limbs were removed after he was face-up.
这里好像是用了不同的工具
Looks like with a -- with a different tool.
大砍刀吗
Machete?
剁刀
Cleaver?
你们是真的不想提起那话题啊
You guys really don't go there?
怎么了
What?
好吧 谁有能砍成这样的工具呢
Okay, who has the tools for this?
你刚才吃的那种面条
Those noodles you had earlier,
面条里面有碎肉 从哪儿来的
there were meat scraps in them -- from where?
屠夫
The butchers.
你不是在说 这是食人行为吧
You're not saying this is cannibalism.
不 我们这儿不干这种事
No. We don't do that up here.
我们都知道关于车尾的那些谣言 但我们
We all know the rumors about the Tail, but we --
那可不是谣言
Oh, those aren't rumors.
最初的几年中 车尾有杀人团体
First couple of years, there were kill cults.
其中有一个团体 他们会杀死任何人
One gang in particular, they would kill anyone,
吃掉任何人
eat anyone.
没有选择
Had no choice.
我们其余的人伏击了他们的首领
The rest of us, we ambushed their leader,
我们每个人都吃下他的一片心脏
each of us ate a piece of his heart
这样就没人可以说自己是无辜的了
so that no one could say they were innocent.
话说 你的午餐好吃吗
Anyway, your lunch was good?
等一下
Hold on.
-你们想要干什么 -请开门
- What do you want? - Open up, please.
我们要看一下你的冷冻库
We need to look in your freezer.
这里是限制区
It's a restricted area.
-司闸员的工作 -我才不管呢
- Brakeman's business. - I don't give a shit.
这里是限制区
It's a restricted area.
你们想进来 先得有公证人
If you want in, get the Notary.
刀不错
Nice knife.
我猜你能用这刀砍下我的腿
Bet you could cut my leg off with that.
我们今天在屠宰
We're butchering today.
找到公证人再来吧
Come back with the Notary.
走吧
Come on.
我猜测这是由于她的沉睡时长
I assume it's due to how long she was under.
我同意 但鉴于要确定这复杂的
I agree, but pinpointing the complex matrix
滴定 时长和分离所组成的矩阵
of titration, duration, isolation,
-就要做... -更多研究 是的
- it's gonna take... - More research, yeah.
或是实验对象 这是个矛盾
Or subjects. It's the catch-22.
情况很糟糕
This is bad.
她可能遭受了永久性的神经损伤
She may have suffered permanent neurological damage.
我们不能正当地...
We can't justify...
我收到了地震警报 情况如何
I've got a seismic alarm. How bad is it?
该死 该死
Mierda. Mierda.
整个山坡正在下滑
The whole slope is coming down.
见鬼
Oh, shit.
这是三级地震
It's a Class 3.
我们不可能从那些废墟中穿过
We're not gonna get through the debris.
抓紧了
Hold on.
做好准备
Brace!
准备撞击
Brace for impact.
出现一个缺口
We got a breach.
在农业区的牲口车厢
Ag-Sec, Cattle Car.
农业区的牲口车厢有一个缺口
We have a breach. Ag-Sec, Cattle Car.
警告 出现缺口
气温 零下42摄氏度
哈维 你来接手
Javi, take over.
好的
Got it.
你还好吗
You okay?
继续往后走
Keep moving back.
让我们进去那里面 我们得搜查冷冻库
Let us back in there. We got to search the freezer.
不 我们正在进行工程救险
No, it's an engineering emergency.
-别碍事 -我们要搜查冷冻库
- Get out of the way. - We got to search the freezer.
-我们是为威尔福德先生工作的 -让开
- We're working for Mr. Wilford. - Out of the way.
-守卫 -维修工
- Jackboot! - Breachman.
好吧 给你们两分钟
Alright, two minutes.
关门
Close the door.
看看这个
Check this out.
我来搞定
Oh, I got it.
冷静点
Hey, hey! Relax.
好的
Oh, yeah, sure.
果然
Yeah.
天啊
Oh, God.
这就是你们的牛肉
Here's your beef.
这位真有意思
How about this one?
她在威尔福德先生手下的乘客服务部工作了七年
Seven years she work hospitality for Mr. Wilford,
而现在来列车后方当工程师
and now she comes ‭downtrain to be engineer.
威尔福德要求她亲自来查看
Wilford asked her to check it personally.
好吧
Okay.
维修工博扬·博斯科维奇 愿为他效劳
Breachman Bojan Boscovic, at his service.
这是一场灭绝事件
It's an extinction event.
抱歉
Sorry.
先补窗户
Window job first.
我们得确保整个结构是否完好
We need to know ‭if it's structurally sound.
我获批可以将速度降低10%
I've been given the okay to reduce speed 10%.
不 不行 对于山区作业来说还是太快了
No, no. Th-That is too fast for mountain work.
-你要降低25% -电量有限
- You give me 25%. - Battery banks.
前方的地形不足以弥补前进的速度
We don't have the terrain ahead to make it up.
或许能我能争取到12%
I can probably get you 12%.
取消头等厢里的按摩浴缸
No Jacuzzis in First.
好
Okay.
开始轮流停电 从车尾开始
So we're on rolling blackouts, starting with the Tail.
小朋友们 20加...
What's 20 plus...
-5等于多少 -25
- 5, for our little ones in the group? - 25.
你得让别人也答答题
You got to give everyone a chance.
结果是26
You got 26.
赶紧的
Hurry up.
这次停电他们会派更多的守卫
They'll send more Jacks for this blackout.
有人来了
Someone's coming.
等会 等会
Hang on, hang on.
给我药
The medicine.
没有止痛药 只有克洛诺
But no painkillers, just Kronole.
我不会把那些垃圾给我妈
I'm -- I'm not giving that crap to my mom.
好吧 但那确实能止痛
Okay, but it kills the pain.
一切的痛
Of everything.
帕特森 你怎么拿到的
Patterson, how?
给
Here you go.
张嘴
Open up.
真棒
Good girl.
好了 苏珊
Okay, Suzanne.
好了
There.
不痛了
Let's stop now.
我们不能再给农业区增加供电了
We can't ration anymore power to Ag-Sec
除非我们减少种植农作物
unless we start canceling crops.
我们不能打破这个循环
We're not breaking rotation.
水至少会停流好几天
Water won't flow for a couple days at least,
直到车体的缺口被修补好
not till the crack in the hull is sealed.
那我们就只有三等厢 农业区和车尾的
Then we only have what's in the reservoir for Third,
蓄水池里的水了
Ag-Sec, and Tail.
我们限量供给人 而不是农作物
We ration the people, not the crops.
二等和三等厢每天会有十五分钟的自来水
Third and Second will get 15 minutes of running water a day,
车尾人就只能靠他们囤积的水生存
and the Tail will have to survive on what they've hoarded.
资源开始崩溃就是这种感觉吗
Is this what the start of a resource crash feels like?
从车尾开始 把人一批批饿死
Starving the train from the Tail lot?
不仅仅是牛肉 还有用作肥料的粪便
It's not just the beef. It's manure for fertilizer.
牛的养殖 我们用它们的甲烷
It's bovine cultures. We use their methane.
我知道 很糟糕
I know. It's bad.
但具体有多糟 只限我们知道
But how bad stays between us.
与此同时 我们继续前进
In the meantime, we press ahead
挑选新的学徒
with selecting the new apprentices,
加强对威尔福德的信心 好让他们坚持下去
and we bolster faith in Wilford to get them through.
尽管你们昨天发动暴乱 而今情势甚危
Despite your violence yesterday, and grave hand of fate
我们都命悬一线
hanging over our heads this very second,
威尔福德先生还是认为 儿童应在需要技术
Mr. Wilford believes that children deserve an education
或体力的劳动中接受教育
in skilled or unskilled labor,
所以我们要进行学徒选拔
and so we are proceeding with apprenticeship selection.
名单如下
The names are as follows.
米卡拉·姆万扎
Mikala Mwanza...
米娅·凯谢克
...Mia Kaisheck...
还有那个被叫做"定心丸"的男孩
...and the boy they call Miles and Miles.
如果你的家人选择接受威尔福德先生的邀请
Should your families choose to accept his invitation,
你有一小时为你在前列车厢的新生活做准备
you have one hour to get ready for your new lives uptrain.
两条腿和一只手臂
Two legs and one arm.
左臂
left arm.
-你能挂断吗 -什么
- Can you hang up? - What?
所有的屠夫都死了 罗切
No, all the butchers are dead, Roche.
听着 杀肖恩的不是屠夫
Hey, look, the butcher didn't kill Sean.
-仔细想一下 -好吧
- Think it through for a second. - Okay.
如果你要杀了他卖肉 那为什么要折磨他
If you're gonna retail him for meat, then why the torture?
好吧
Okay.
不管凶手是谁 他们从阉割中获得了快感
Whoever did it got off on castrating him.
但砍掉手臂和腿则完全相反
But the arms and legs were the exact opposite.
完全不带情绪
No emotion at all.
所以屠夫是第二个动手的
So the butchers come second.
他把手臂和腿上的肉放进我的面条里
He puts arms and legs in my fricking noodles.
车尾人
Tailie.
放松
Easy.
滚开 混蛋
Back off, douche.
车尾舔狗
Tail-sucker.
害咱俩都被揍可没好处
There is no use getting us both shitkicked.
跟你有什么关系
Yeah, what do you care?
干脆把罪名甩给屠夫 认领你的三等厢房间
Just blame the butchers and claim your Third Class cabin.
首先 我不想去三等厢
First off, I don't want Third Class.
我想回到车尾 第二...
I want to go back to the Tail. And second...
看来我还是一名警察
Guess I'm still a cop, after all.
我当时也负责调查第一桩谋杀案
I was assigned to the first murder, too.
他们一开始就认定是妮基干的
They had Nikki guilty out of the gate.
快速审讯 一共才花了三小时
Fast tribunal -- took all of three hours.
我完全没法帮助她
Nothing I could've done for her.
你还想要抓到真正的凶手吗
You still care about getting the right guy?
我终于在冰箱里找到了你的四肢
I finally got into the freezer and recovered your limbs.
真是个好日子
Pretty good day.
谢谢
Thanks.
顺便 她很擅长这个环节
She's good at this part, by the way,
在墙角搜身男孩
patting down the boys on the corner.
晚安 警探
Good night, Detective.
继续往前
Keep it moving.
回到车尾前不准抬头
Eyes down till you're back in the Tail.
低头
Eyes down.
继续往前
Keep moving.
来抓我啊 混蛋
Come and get me, asshole!
起来 起来
Hey, get off! Get off! Hey!
莱顿
Layton!
趴下
Get on the ground!
你还记得你妈妈吗 迈尔斯
Do you remember your mum, Miles?
我...
I...
我记得...
I remember...
她很香
...she smelled good.
就这样吗
That's all?
我的记忆只有这辆列车
I only remember the train.
你是我的车尾妈妈
You're my Tail mum.
定心丸啊
Miles and Miles.
定心丸
Miles and Miles
还有迈尔斯 迈尔斯 迈尔斯 迈尔斯
and Miles, Miles, Miles, Miles, Miles, Miles, Miles, Miles.
我们刚来的时候你还是一个小家伙
You were so little when we started.
我现在不是了
I'm not anymore.
那好吧
Well, then,
那你现在该自己做决定了吧
you better decide for yourself, don't you?
莱顿说我们要让我们的人去前列车厢
Layton says we need our people uptrain.
他说得没错
He's right.
我们需要每个部门都有人
We need every department.
我们要在各个阶层都有朋友
We need friends high and low.
你看
You see?
你是一个很好的聆听者
You are a good listener.
迈尔斯
Miles...
我发誓
I swear to you,
我不会停止从后方战斗
I will not stop fighting from the back.
但你得去前方
But you're going uptrain.
那意味着我们或许永远不会再见面
And that means we might never see each other again.
我们会的
Yes, we will.
就像莱顿所说的 在革命之后
After the revolution, like Layton said.
好吗
Alright?
爱你
Love you.
你看着这辆火车的时候
What do you see...
你能看到什么
...when you look at this train?
我看到一座堡垒
I see a fortress to class.
就没了吗
Is that all?
我看到三千个挣扎活着的灵魂
Well, I see 3,000 souls surviving
在一个注定要冻结所有生命的星球上
on a planet that's determined to freeze all life in place.
我们还在运行中
We're still in motion,
生机勃勃
alive and kicking,
这不是因为机遇 命运或者上帝
and it's not thanks to chance or fate or God.
而是因为由威尔福德先生
It is thanks to order,
小心翼翼维护的秩序
meticulously maintained by Mr. Wilford.
在需求 贪婪和速度之间的平衡
A balance of need and greed and speed,
而你们车尾人 似乎忘了
and you Tailies, who seem to have forgotten
车厢外气温是零下117度
that it is 117 degrees below zero outside of this metal tube,
而威尔福德先生一天有21小时都是醒着的
and Mr. Wilford is awake 21 hours a day
就为了保持列车内有暖气
just to keep the Goddamn heat on.
我想这就是为什么需要肖恩·怀斯那样的线人吧
Guess that's why it needs informants like Sean Wise.
怀斯是威尔福德的特务
Wise was a Wilford rat.
他的回报就是各种特别待遇
He got paid in perks...
比如作弊的婴儿彩
like the rigged Baby Lottery.
不然你为什么要如此关心一个三等厢人的死
Why else would you care so much about a Thirdie's murder?
所以 你真正想知道的是
So, what you really want to know is,
他被折磨的时候 他说出了哪些关于威尔福德的秘密
when he was tortured, what Wilford secrets did he spill?
你在这里有杀手 食人者
Y'all got killers and cannibals
天知道还有什么
and God-knows what else up here.
所以别跟我扯平衡那一套
So don't lecture me about balance.
我的人多年前就找到了我们的平衡
My people found ours years ago.
好
Okay.
很有洞察力
Very perceptive.
难怪威尔福德先生想让你做列车警探
No wonder Mr. Wilford wants you as Train Detective.
但那是你仍然还活着的唯一原因
But that's the only reason you're still here now.